Finding Aid for the Stanley Kramer Papers LSC.0161
UCLA Library Special Collections
- PART 2: Additions, May 1978.
  - Transcripts.
    - United States of America vs.. Tomoyuki Yamashita., TRANSCRIPTS.
      - 15. Pages 2907-3128. (Box 289)
      - 16. Pages 3129-3312. (Box 289)
      - 17. Pages 3313-3522. (Box 289)
      - 18. Pages 3523-3759. (Box 289)
      - 19. Pages 3760-4063. (Box 290)
    - Julius Rosenberg and Ethel Rosenberg, petitioners, vs.. The United States of America. no. 111.
      - 1. Pages 1-666. (Box 290)
      - 2. Pages 667-890. (Box 290)
      - 3. Pages 891-1098. (Box 290)
      - 4. Pages 1099-1306. (Box 290)
      - 5. Pages 1307-1514. (Box 290)
      - 6. Pages 1515-1715. (Box 290)
  - Depositions and Exhibits.
    - Joseph Than and Elick Moll, Plaintiffs, vs.. Columbia Pictures Corporation, Stanley Kramer, Sidney Poitier, William Rose, Defendants. no. 926,425, Superior Court of Los Angeles.
      - 1. Trial brief and notes on depositions of Stanley Kramer and William Rose. (Box 290)
      - 2. Deposition of E. Henry Lewis., October 17, 1969. (Box 290)
      - 3. Deposition of Stanley Kramer. vol. 1., January 20, 1969. (Box 291)
      - 4. Deposition of Stanley Kramer. vol. 2., January 24, 1969. (Box 291)
      - 5. Deposition of Joseph Than. vol. 1., August 6, 1969. (Box 291)
      - 6. Deposition of Joseph Than. vol. 2., August 7, 1969. (Box 291)
      - 7. Deposition of Sidney Poitier., April 11, 1969. (Box 291)
      - 8. Deposition of Elias (Elick) Moll., August 11-12, 1969. (Box 291)
      - 9. Deposition of William Arthur Rose. London, May 28-29, 1969. (Box 291)
      - 10. Exhibit A: A Distant Light by J. Than and Elick Moll. (Box 291)
      - 11. Book of exhibits. (Box 291)
      - 1. Wooden box. Gift to Stanley Kramer from U.S.S.R. Containing ashes from Hiroshima. (Ashes removed by Kramer.) (Box 292)
      - 2. I hate everybody button. (Box 292)
      - 3. Domino Principle. Cardboard acknowledgement from crew to Stanley Kramer. Inscribed by crew members. (Box 357)
      - 4. Research. Rosenberg trial. Wolper Productions., 8, 1975. (Box 292)
      - 5. Trials research. Judgment file., February 1973. (Box 292)
      - 6. Envelope containing photographs of Karen Black (5). With note from Phil Kellogg. (Box 292)
      - 7. Envelope containing photographs of Stanley Kramer (5). (Box 292)
      - 8. Stills of Stanley Kramer. ca. 100. (Box 292)
      - 9. Stills of Stanley Kramer and others (41). (Box 293)
      - 10. Author Artist Album, vol. 10, University of Women of the University of Judaism., 1976. (Box 293)
      - 11. Scientific or Technical Award Entries--50th Annual Academy Awards, 1977. (Box 293)
      - 12. Southern California Council of Churches Award. Los Angeles Press Club. Proofs., March 13, 1968.; 2 items. (Box 293)
      - 13. Klein, Barzman and Hecht. Description of company., April 3, 1969. (Box 293)
      - 14. Letters to Kramer re his appearance on the David Frost television show concerning gun control. 24 items., ca. 1971-1972. (Box 293)
      - 15. Memo re stills of various productions., August 11, 1971. (Box 293)
      - 16. Brochure. U.S. Dept. of Labor., ca. 1967. (Box 293)
      - 17. Judgment. Trials research., February 1973. (Box 293)
      - 18. Judgment. Kramer/Wolper Productior., March 1973. (Box 293)
      - 19. Judgment. Kramer/Wolper Production., April 1973. (Box 293)
      - 20. Judgment research., ca. 1973. (Box 293)
  - Additional Production Material
    - Stills. (Box 299)
      - Various., 15 pieces. (Box 299, Folder 5)
      - Master list and film inventory., ca. 60 leaves, 2 copies. (Box 299, Folder 6)
      - Mike Beck - publicity and correspondence. Production material list., 2 leaves, 4 copies. (Box 299, Folder 7)
    - Additions, February 1983.
      - Certificate of Recognition from the Directors Guild of America, presented to Stanley Kramer, November 28, 1982. (Box 299, Folder 10)
      - Resolution designating Stanley Kramer Artist-in-Residence. Bellevue Community College District 8. Bellevue, Washington, In black frame., May 13, 1980. (Box 299, Folder 11)
      - Medal. Ville de Deauville. Stanley Kramer, September 1979. (Box 299, Folder 12)
      - Certificate designating Gold Award at Moscow Film Festival for Oklahoma Crude, 1973. (Box 357)
    - Additions, June 1983. (Box 299)
      - Award. San Jose Film Society, Presented to Stanley Kramer for consistency and integrity in bringing motion pictures of social relevance to the screen. Mounted on walnut placque., 20.5 × 30.5 cm. 1 item. (Folder 13)
      - Honorary degree. Doctorate of Fine Arts. Linfield College, McMinnville, Oregon, 20 × 15 cm. In case. 1 item. With this: copy of remarks by Charles U. Walker, academic hood, and 2 copies of baccalaureate and commencement programs., May 29, 1983. (Box 300, Folder 1)
      - John Ford Medallion. Presented to Stanley Kramer. U.S. Film and Video Festival. Utah, 1 item. 2 bronze medallions mounted on oak plaque., January 30, 1982.; 50.5 × 25.5 cm. (Box 362)
      - Certificate of recognition awarded to Stanley Kramer,, at the Moscow Film Festival for Humanism in cinema art, For peace and friendship among nations!, July 1983 (Box 362)
      - Festival Des Films Du Monde, Montreal. Includes newsclippings, film schedule, program, SK itinerary, correspondence re Film Makers Assembly, party invitation and 8 photos of SK and fans., August, 1983. (Box 300, Folder 2)
        Addition, September 1983.
      - Bronze medallion with brass trim presented To Stanley Kramer for Life Achievement. Montreal World Film Festival, In a bright blue velvet case., 1983. (Folder 3)
      - Certificate awarded to Stanley Kramer for life achievement in cinematography presented at the Festival Des Films Du Monde, Montréal,, mounted on a wooden plaque., August 20, 1983 (Box 362)
      - Israel Humanities Achievement Award presented to Stanley Kramer in recognition of his outstanding contributions to the arts, his firm support of human rights, and his devoted service to the State of Israel. New York City, In gilt wood frame with print by NGL(?) Stern., May 14, 1984.; Print: 67 (w) × 58.5 cm. (h); certificate: 35 × 27.5 cm.: framed print & certificate: 81 cm. × 107.5 cm.
      - --Production 8490., Andersonville; (72 items) (Box 326)
        Original drawings, general preliminary drawings, tracings, and finish drawings.
      - Production 8490 Prints [architectural drawings]., 12 items. (Box 327)
      - County of Los Angeles Resolution, 1970. (Box 357)
      - City of Los Angeles Resolution, 1971